A Finding Aid to the Louis Bouché papers, 1880-2007, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1900-1997; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 3, 6
  - Journals, Poetry, 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Portfolio of Work: Louis Bouché, Allen Saalburg, and Everett Henry, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6, Folder 4
  - Report, Tenant-Owned Apartment Association, Inc., 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Oversized Books, Exposition Universelle, Paris 1900; L'Aeronautique 1783-1922; Le Panorama, Exposition Universalle scanned with Box 3, Folder 10, circa 1900-1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Clippings scanned with Box 3, Folder 11, circa 1930-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Penguin Club scanned with Box 3, Folder 17, 1917-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Portfolio of Work: Louis Bouché, Allen Saalburg, and Everett Henry scanned with Box 3, Folder 22, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Scrapbooks, 1880-1969; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 3, 7-8
  Two scrapbooks include clippings, photographs, and printed material related to Bouché's career. One scrapbook documents the history of the extended Bouché family, including Ernest, Henri, and Claire, compiled by Marie Bouché. It includes clippings, photographs, catalogs, written memoirs, geneology charts, and drawings by Jane Bouché and Claire's son Peter. The final scrapbook consists of reproductions of works of art by Pierre Bonnard, Edouard Vuillard, Toulouse-Lautrec, Edgar Degas, and Chaim Soutine.
  Scrapbooks created by Louis Bouché and his immediate family are followed by scrapbooks created by extended family members.
  - Scrapbook I, Louis Bouché, 1915-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Oversized material housed in Box 7
  - Scrapbook II, Louis Bouché, 1945-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Oversized material housed in Box 8
  - Bouché Family, circa 1880-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - French Artists, circa 1930-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Oversized Scrapbook, Scrapbook I, Louis Bouché scanned with Box 3, Folder 24, 1915-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 7)
  - Oversized Scrapbook, Scrapbook II, Louis Bouché scanned with Box 3, Folder 25, 1945-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Scrapbook, French Artists, scanned with Box 3, Folder 27, circa 1930-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Photographic Materials, 1890-1994; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 3-5, 9-10
  Photographic materials include ten photograph albums. Three are of Louis, Marian, and Jane, three are of Jane and her family, and four are of Louis' parents and sister's family. There are also loose prints and negatives of Bouché, his family and friends, and copyprints of works of art, including works of art that were destroyed. Included in the loose prints of Bouché are photographs taken by Carl Van Vechten, Hal Phyfe, Herbert Gehr, and Drix Duryea.
  Photograph albums created by Louis Bouché and his immediate family are followed by albums created by extended family members.
  - Album, Louis, Marian, and Jane Bouché, circa 1915-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9
  - Album, Louis, Marian, and Jane Bouché, circa 1920-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Album, Louis, Marian, and Jane Bouché, circa 1940-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Album, Jane Bouché and William Pène du Bois, circa 1945-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Album, Jane Bouché and William Pène du Bois, circa 1945-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Album, Jane Bouché Strong, circa 1900-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 1
  - Album, Bouché Family, circa 1890-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Album, Bouché Family, circa 1890-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Album, Bouché Family, circa 1890-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Album, Claire Bouché Whiton and Family, circa 1906-1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Album, Loose Photographs, circa 1908-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Louis Bouché, 1897-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 2
  - Photographs of Louis and Marian Bouché, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Negatives of Louis and Marian Bouché, European Vacation, circa 1950-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Louis and Jane Bouché, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Louis Bouché with Friends, circa 1910-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Louis Bouché with New York World's Fair Project Model, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Louis Bouché with Murals, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Oversized materials housed in Box 10, Folder 2
  - Photographs of Marian Bouché, circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of Jane Bouché, circa 1920-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Photographs of Friends, Brook, Alexander, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Friends, Jones, Edward, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Photographs of the Bouché Family, circa 1880-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Bouché Family Home in NYC, circa 1880-1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Photographs of the Whiton Family, 1900-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Whiton Family Home in Wilton, CT, circa 1940-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Exhibitions, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Louis Bouché, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Destroyed, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Murals, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Murals, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Men, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Men and Women, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Women, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Women, Nudes, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Landscapes, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Outdoor Scenes, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Outdoor Scenes, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Outdoor Scenes, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Indoor Scenes, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Still Life, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Oversized Album, Louis, Marian, and Jane Bouché scanned with Box 4, Folders 28, 30, circa 1915-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 9)
  - Oversized Album, Jane Bouché Strong scanned with Box 4, Folder 2, circa 1900-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Photographs of Louis Bouché scanned with Box 4, Folder 8, circa 1920-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Photographs of Louis and Jane Bouché scanned with Box 4, Folder 11, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Photographs of Louis Bouché with Murals scanned with Box 4, Folder 14, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Artwork, 1870-1965; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 10 Folders Boxes 5, 10
  Artwork consists of sketches and drawings by Louis; a childhood collection of drawings by Jane; watercolors, etchings and monographs by Henri; and a pencil sketchbook of landscape scenes by Ernest Bouché. Additional sketches by Peggy Bacon, Alexander Brook, Jo Davidson, and Reginald Marsh are also included.
  Materials are arranged by artist.
  - Bacon, Peggy, Sketches, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 3
  - Bouché, Ernest Louis, Sketchbook, 1890-1898; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bouché, Henri L., Monograms for Tiffany, circa 1880-1908; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bouché, Henri L., Watercolors and Sketches, circa 1870-1908; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Bouché, Jane, Sketches, circa 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bouché, Louis, Sketches and Watercolor, circa 1900-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Brook, Alexander, Sketch, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Davidson, Jo, Sketch, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Marsh, Reginald, Sketch, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Unknown, Drawings and Sketches, circa 1910-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Oversized Sketches by Peggy Bacon scanned with Box 5, Folder 10, circa 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Sketch by Alexander Brook scanned with Box 5, Folder 16, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)